Guide to the Frank Richard Oastler Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Frank Richard Oastler collection.
1908-1938
WA MSS S-2162
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
127
(253 boxes) + 3 broadsides
The collection consists of photograph albums, lantern slides, and photographic negatives documenting Oastler's interest in wildlife and conservation, from 1909-1938. The 68 photograph albums document the Oastlers' trips to the West and elsewhere. Approximately 6400 lantern slides, most of them hand-colored, were used for Dr. Oastler's lectures on the West, and include nine panoramic lantern slides.
Oastler, Frank Richard, 1871-1936
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Maude Matthews Oastler in memory of Dr. Frank Richard Oastler. Transferred from the School of Forestry to Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, 1983. Transferred from Manuscripts and Archives to Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University, 1998.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
The Cut Film Negatives and Restricted Fragile Papers (boxes 238-239 and 241-252) may only be consulted with permission of the appropriate curator.
Associated Materials
204 black and white 16mm motion picture films documenting the Oastlers' Western trips and visits to other national parks, accompanied by various descriptive notes, transferred to Library of Congress, Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, National Audio-Visual Conservation Center, 2012.
FRANK RICHARD OASTLER (1871-1936)
Frank Richard Oastler, Yale College Class of 1891, was a surgeon by profession and also an amateur photographer, scholar, and authority on wildlife conservation and its interpretation to the public. Upon graduating from Yale, Oastler attended Columbia University's medical school, and graduated with the degree of M.D. in 1894. He became a surgeon specializing in gynecology, and was a professor of surgery at Columbia University from 1912 to 1932, when he retired. Known as an authority in his field, he was a member of many medical associations, and head of the department of gynecology at Lenox Hill Hospital in New York until his death in 1936.
Dr. Oastler spent his summers exploring the mountains of the United States and Canadian West, traveling by pack train, photographing the landscapes, fauna, and flora he encountered. He brought home both still and motion pictures which he used in lectures to teach others about natural history and conservation. He was sought after as an authority on the American wilderness, is credited with being chiefly responsible for saving the trumpeter swan from extinction, and instituted the National Park Service's public education program. He advocated nature walks, museums, and nature lectures. He served as a member of the Advisory Board of the National Park Service and was a leader in the movement to create the Isle Royale National Park in Michigan.
In the summer of 1936 Dr. Oastler died of a heart attack while traveling with his wife Maude in Glacier National Park, Montana.
Scope and Contents
The Frank Richard Oastler Collection consists of photograph albums, lantern slides, movie film, and photographic negatives documenting his interest in wildlife and conservation, from 1908-1938. The Collection is comprised of four series: Photograph Albums, Lantern Slides, Photographic Negatives, Film Surrogates and is housed in 253 boxes. The collection does not include any significant collection of Oastler's personal papers. There are a few letters preserved with the photograph albums, and a few instances of writings in them as well.
Series I, Photograph Albums, 1912-1935, undated (boxes 1-69), consists of albums documenting the Oastlers' trips to the West and elsewhere and is arranged chronologically. Many of the albums are captioned, in manuscript, by the Oastlers. There are a small number of hand-colored photographs. While most of the photographs in the albums were taken by Oastler, a few commercial photographs and photographic postcards are also present. Commercial photographers whose work appears in the albums include Cross & Dimmitt; Asahel Curtis; T. Davis; Foster Photo Co. (Miles City, Montana); E.R. Freeman Photo; F. Gowen; Gurr Photo; Byron Harmon (Banff, Canada); Kiser Photo Co. (Portland, Oregon); L.D. Lindsley; Smith's Photo; Thieman [?] (Kalispell, Montana); Jim Thompson Co. (Knoxville, Tennessee); A. Wilkes; and Winter & Pond Co. (Juneau, Alaska).
The albums include items laid in loose; their presence has been noted in the finding aid. Those items which when flattened were too large to fit into the album have been removed to a separate box at the end of the series, or have been placed in Oversize, as appropriate. The early albums also occasionally include other textual material: a typescript account of a trip to Glacier National Park, Montana (box 3), a holograph poem for a drowned horse (box 8), a list of a guide's vocabulary (box 10).
Series II, Lantern Slides, consists of approximately 6400 lantern slides used for Dr. Oastler's lectures on the West. (Scripts for these lectures, however, are not present.) Most of the slides are hand-colored; some duplicate images in the photograph albums. The hand coloring was done by Mildred Petry, under the direct supervision of Dr. Oastler. The lantern slides are organized into two subseries: Lantern Slides in Oastler's Classification (ca. 5500 slides), and Unclassified Lantern Slides.
A combination of classification indices and topical indices, portions of which are replicated in this finding aid, provide detailed geographic and topical subject access to the slide collection. A key to the classification system can be found in a bound typescript in box 80. The first letter and number of the classification (e.g. A2) refers to the place in which the photograph was taken; for convenience, the finding aid includes these places as headings in the box listing. This listing, therefore, provides fairly detailed geographic access to the slides. A card index to the slides (boxes 70-79) provides more detailed topical subject access, by animal, plant name, etc. The cards also include the text of captions for each slide, which also appear on the slide casing. The card index appears to be very nearly complete, and includes cards for slides present in the collection but not included in the classification index. There are also cards for slides which are not now present in the collection. These missing slides have been noted in the corresponding box description in the finding aid. The topical headings employed in the card index, including types of flora, fauna, and place names depicted have been listed in Appendix I. Both the classification system and card index were received with the collection, and presumably were created either by the Oastlers or under their direct supervision.
The Unclassified Lantern Slides are organized into Panoramic Lantern Slides and Other Lantern Slides. There are nine panoramic lantern slides, which measure 8 x 25 cm. Other Lantern Slides include three sets of slides still in the traveling cases that Dr. Oastler used for his lectures (boxes 233-235). These traveling cases, labeled "Alaska Lecture," "Canadian Rockies Lecture," and "Isle Royale National Park, Michigan" include a few slides of other places as well. Not all of the slides in the traveling cases are captioned, but all are arranged and numbered in order of presentation during the lectures.
Series III, Photographic Negatives, 1920, undated (box 237), is organized into two subseries: Glass Plate Negatives and Cut Film Negatives. The glass plate negatives are a miscellaneous assortment of forty-five glass plate negatives. In addition to the contents of box 237, there are approximately eight boxes of cut film nitrate negatives, which are restricted. They are presumed to correspond to the prints assembled in the albums (Series I). For further information, contact the Western Americana curator.
Series IV. Film Surrogates contains four copies of films made by Frank Richard Oastler that record undated trips to Glacier National Park and to Yellowstone National Park, a trip down the Colorado River in 1925, and a trip to Alaska in 1927. The original films were badly deteriorated and the Beinecke Library pursued extensive conservation of these four prior to the transfer of the films to the Library of Congress.
Oversize, broadside folders 294-295a, contains material from Series I and II, and is arranged in box order.
Restricted Fragile Papers in Boxes 238-239 consist of originals for which preservation photocopies have been made.
Appendix I: Lantern Slide Card Index Headings
The card index may be found in boxes 70-79. The headings that appear in the card list have been given here as an indication of the access available to the lantern slides.
Air plant
Alaska - Animals
Alaska - Birds
Alaska - Fish
Alaska - Flowers
Alaska - Miscellaneous
Alaska - Scenic
Alaska - Trees
Alder
Alligator
Anhinga
Anemone
Antelope
Antiquities
Apache Indians
Apple
Arch Canyon - Scenic
Arches National Monument - Animals
Arches National Monument - Scenic
Arum, Water
Ash
Ash, Mountain
Aspen
Aspen, Quaking
Aster
Avocet
Azalea
Badger
Balsam Root
Baneberry
Bayberry
Bear
Bear, Black
Bear, Brown
Bear, Cinnamon
Bear, Grizzly
Bear, Kodiak
Bear River - Birds
Bear River - Scenic
Beardtongue
Beaver
Bee Flower
Bee Plant
Beech
Bellwort
Bergamot
Berries
Betony, Wood
Birch
Birch, Gray
Birch, Paper
Birch, White
Bittern
Bittersweet
Blackberry
Blackbird
Black-eyed Susan
Blackfoot Indians
Bladder Campion
Bleeding Heart
Bloodroot
Blue bell
Bluebird
Bob cat
Bouncing Bet
British Columbia - Animals
British Columbia - Flowers
British Columbia - Miscellaneous
British Columbia - Scenic
Bryce Canyon - Flowers
Bryce Canyon - Scenic
Bryce Canyon - Trees
Buck brush
Buckthorn
Buffalo
Buffalo berry
Buffalo bird
Bunch berry
Bunting
Burning Bush
Burro
Butter and Eggs
Buttercup
Butterfly
Butterfly Weed
Button-ball
Buzzard
Cactus
Calapagon
California - Birds
California - Flowers
California - Scenic
California - Trees
Camass
Canada
Canadian Rocky Mts. - Animals
Canadian Rocky Mts. - Birds
Canadian Rocky Mts. - Fish
Canadian Rocky Mts. - Flowers
Canadian Rocky Mts. - Miscellaneous
Canadian Rocky Mts. - Scenic
Canadian Rocky Mountains - Trees
Canterbury bells
Caribou
Cascade Mountain Region - Birds
Cascade Mountain Region - Flowers
Cascade Mountain Region - Miscellaneous
Cascade Mountain Region - Scenic
Cascade Mountain Region - Trees
Cassiope
Cat
Cat-tail
Cattle
Cauliferae
Cedar
Century plant
Cherry
Chestnut
Chipmunk
Chokecherry
Chrysopsis
Cinque foil
Civet Cat
Clintonia
Clover
Colorado River region - Animals
Colorado River region - Birds
Colorado River region - Flowers
Colorado River region - Miscellaneous
Colorado River region - Scenic
Colorado River region - Trees
Colored glass
Columbine
Coney
Cone, Pine
Connecticut - Bird
Connecticut - Scenic
Coot
Coral root
Cormorant
Corn
Corn flower
Corn, Prehistoric
Cottonwood
Coyote
Crab
Crane, Sandhill
Crassulaceae
Crater Lake National Park - Animals
Crater Lake National Park - Scenic
Crater Lake National Park - Trees
Cricket
Crossbeak
Crossbill
Crow
Cuicopin
Curlew
Currant
Cypress
Daisy
Dandelion
Darning needle
Deer
Deer, Black-tailed
Deer, Mule
Deer, Virginia
Deer, White-tailed Arizona
Delphinium
Devil's club
Devil's Garden region - Scenic
Dog
Dogwood
Donkey
Dove
Dryas
Duck
Duck, Baldpate
Duck, Black
Duck, Canvasback
Duck, Mallard
Duck, Mud
Duck, Pintail
Duck, Redheaded
Duck, Ring-necked
Duck, Ruddy
Duck, Scaup
Duck, Wood
Duck, Yellow-eyed
Dutchman's breeches
Eagle
Eggs
Egret
Egret, American
Egret, Brewster's
Egret, Reddish
Egret, Snowy
Elderberry
Elk
Elk, Spike-horned
Elkslip
Elm
Everlasting
Erigeron
False Snapdragon
Farming
Ferns
Finch
Fir
Fire-cracker plant
Fireweed
Flag, Blue
Flax
Flea-bane
Fleur-de-lis
Flicker
Flies
Florida - Birds
Florida - Flowers
Florida - Scenic
Florida - Trees
Flowers
Flycatcher
Forget-me-not
Fossils
Four o'clocks
Fox, Blue
Fox, Silver
Frog
Frog, Tree
Fungi
Gadwell
Gaillardia
Gallinule
Gentian
Geranium
Gilia
Glacier National Park - Animals
Glacier National Park - Birds
Glacier National Park - Flowers
Glacier National Park - Miscellaneous
Glacier National Park - Scenic
Glacier National Park - Trees
Goat
Goat, Rocky Mountain
Goldenrod
Goose
Gopher
Goshawk
Grand Canyon - Animals
Grand Canyon - Flowers
Grand Canyon - Miscellaneous
Grand Canyon - Scenic
Grand Canyon - Trees
Grand Teton National Park - Scenic
Grass
Grasshopper
Grebe
Greenbriar
Grouse
Gulf of Mexico - Birds
Gull
Gull, California
Gull, Franklin's
Gull, Glaucous
Gull, Herring
Gull, Laughing
Gull, Ring-billed
Gull, Ring-necked
Harebell
Havasupai Indians
Hawk, Cooper
Hawk, Fish
Hawk, Marsh
Hawk, Night
Hawkweed
Hawthorn
Heather
Heliotrope
Hemlock
Heron
Heron, Black-crowned Night
Heron, Blue
Heron, Great Blue
Heron, Green
Heron, Little Blue
Heron, Little Green
Heron, Louisiana
Heron, Snowy
Heron, Treganza
Heron, Ward's
Heron, White
Heron, Yellow-crowned Night
High Sierra Region - Animals
High Sierra Region - Birds
High Sierra Region - Flowers
High Sierra Region - Miscellaneous
High Sierra Region - Scenic
High Sierra Region - Trees
Holly
Hollyhock
Hopi Indians
Hornet's Nest
Horse
Huckleberry
Hummingbird
Hybiscus
Hyacinth
Ibis, White
Ibis, White-faced Glossy
Ibis, Wood
Idaho - Animals
Idaho - Birds
Idaho - Flowers
Idaho - Fish
Idaho - Miscellaneous
Idaho - Scenic
Idaho - Trees
Indian pipes (flower)
Indians
Iris
Ironwood
Isle Royale - Animals
Isle Royale - Birds
Isle Royale - Flowers
Isle Royale - Miscellaneous
Isle Royale - Scenic
Isle Royale - Trees
Ivy, Poison
Jack-in-the-Pulpit
Jay
Jimson weed
Joe Pye weed
Joshua tree
Junco
Juniper
Kaibab Region - Animals
Kaibab Region - Scenic
Kangaroo rat
Killdeer
Kingbird
Kingfisher
Knot
Labrador tea
Ladies Tresses
Lady Slipper
Larch
Laurel
Leucosticte
Lenum
Lilac Lily
Limpkin
Lion
Lizard
Locust (tree)
Loon
Loose strife
Louisiana - Birds
Louisiana - Miscellaneous
Louisiana - Scenic
Lousewort
Lunch
Lupine
Mallow
Mangrove
Manzanita
Map
Maple
Maple, Red
Maple, Red (Swamp)
Maple, Vine
Maple, Yellow
Marigold
Marmot
Marmot, Hoary
Marten
Massachusetts - Animals
Massachusetts - Scenic
Mayflower
Meadow Rue
Mesa Verde National Park - Flowers
Mesa Verde National Park - Miscellaneous
Mesa Verde National Park - Scenic
Mesquite tree
Mexico - Animals
Mexico - Scenic
Mexico - Trees
Milkweed
Mimulus
Mint
Miscellaneous
Mississippi - Birds
Mistletoe
Mitrewort
Mocking bird
Moneses
Monkey flower
Monkshood
Montana - Animals
Montana - Birds
Montana - Flowers
Montana - Miscellaneous
Montana - Scenic
Moonflower
Moose
Morning-glory
Moss
Moth mullin
Mt. Hood Region - Animals
Mt. Hood Region - Scenic
Mt. Rainier National Park - Animals
Mt. Rainier National Park - Birds
Mt. Rainier National Park - Flowers
Mt. Rainier National Park - Miscellaneous
Mt. Rainier National Park - Scenic
Mt. Rainier National Park - Trees
Muir, John
Mule
Mullen
Muskrat
Natural Bridges National Monument - Scenic
Natural Bridges Region - Scenic
Navajo Indians
New Brunswick - Animals
New Brunswick - Birds
New Brunswick - Flowers
New Brunswick - Miscellaneous
New Brunswick - Scenic
New Jersey - Birds
New Mexico - Animals
New Mexico - Birds
New Mexico - Flowers
New Mexico - Miscellaneous
New Mexico - Scenic
New Mexico - Trees
New York - Animals
New York - Birds
New York - Flowers
New York - Miscellaneous
New York - Scenic
New York - Trees
Nine-bark flower
North Carolina - Animals
Nutcracker, Clark's
Nuthatch
Oak
Oak, Black
Oastler, F.R.
Oastler Castle
Ocatilla
Olympic Region - Animals
Olympic Region - Birds
Olympic Region - Flowers
Olympic Region - Miscellaneous
Olympic Region - Scenic
Olympic Region - Trees
Orchid
Osprey
Ouray Region - Scenic
Ouzel
Owl
Oyster Catcher
Paintbrush
Palm
PaloVerde tree
Pantella
Papago Indian
Parnassus
Pasque flower
Passion Flower
Peach
Pear
Pelican
Pelican, Brown
Pelican, White
Pennsylvania - Scenic
Pentstemon
Petrified Forest
Petrified Wood
Phacelia
Phaenopepla
Phalarope
Phlox
Phoebe, Say
Pig
Pine
Pine, Fox-tail
Pine, Jeffrey
Pine, Sugar
Pine, White
Pine, Yellow
Pine cones
Pinesap
Pipsisewa
Pitcher Plant
Piute Indians
Plover
Pokeberry
Poplar
Poppy
Porcupine
Potentilla
Primrose
Ptarmigan
Pumpkin
Pussy Paw flower
Pussy willow
Pyrola
Quail
Queen's Cup
Rabbit
Raccoon
Rail, Clapper
Rail, Sora
Rainbow Bridge Region - Scenic
Rattlesnake
Raven
Redstart
Redwood
Rhododendron
Robin
Rochambeau house
Rocky Mountain National Park - Animals
Rocky Mountain National Park - Flowers
Rocky Mountain National Park - Scenic
Rose, Rambler
Rose, Rock
Rose, Wild
Rudbeckia
Sage hen
Salmon
Salmon berry
Sandpiper
Sarsaparilla
Saxifrage
Scoter
Seal
Sequoia
Service berry
Shad bush
Sheep
Sheep, Dall
Sheep, Rocky Mountain
Shin leaf
Shooting Star Flower
Shoveller
Shrike
Skimmer, Black
Skunk Cabbage
Sky Pilot
Smoke Bush
Smoky Mountain National Park - Scenic
Snake
Snake root
Snipe
Snow plant
Soapweed
Solomon Seal
South Carolina - Birds
South Carolina - Flowers
South Carolina - Miscellaneous
South Carolina - Scenic
South Carolina - Trees
Spanish Moss
Sparrow
Spice bush
Spider Web
Spirea
Spoonbill
Spring Beauty
Spruce
Squirrel
Star Flower
Starling
Stilt, Black-necked
Starling
Stonecrop
Stork
Strawberry
Sumach
Sun, Eclipse
Sunflower
Swallow
Swan, Trumpeter
Sweet pea
Switzerland - Scenic
Taos Indians
Tarantula
Tattler
Teal
Tern
Tern, Black
Tern, Cabot's
Tern, Caspian
Tern, Forster
Tern, Gullbilled
Tern, Least
Tern, Royal
Texas - Birds
Texas - Flowers
Texas - Miscellaneous
Texas - Scenic
Thistle
Titlark
Title-slide
Toad
Toothwort
Total eclipse
Tradescantia
Trees
Trillium
Trout
Turnstone
Tulip tree
Turtle
Twin Flowers
Uncompahgre Region - Scenic
Valerian
Veneophilia
Vetch
Viburnum
Violet
Virginia - Birds
Virginia creeper
Virginia - Miscellaneous
Virginia - Scenic
Warbler
Water Willow Herb
Waxwing, Cedar
Weasel
Welcome Stranger
White Canyon Region - Flowers
White Canyon Region - Scenic
Willet
Willow
Window Castles Region - Scenic
Wintergreen
Woodpecker
Wren
Wyoming National Forest - Scenic
Yaeger
Yellowstone National Park - Animals
Yellowstone Region - Animals
Yellowstone National Park - Birds
Yellowstone Region - Birds
Yellowstone National Park - Flowers
Yellowstone Region - Flowers
Yellowstone region - Miscellaneous
Yellowstone National Park - Petrified wood
Yellowstone National Park - Scenic
Yellowstone Region - Scenic
Yellowstone Region - Trees
Yosemite National Park - Animals
Yosemite National Park - Birds
Yosemite National Park - Flowers
Yosemite National Park - Scenic
Yosemite National Park - Trees
Yucca
Zion National Park - Animals
Zion National Park Region - Flowers
Zion National Park - Miscellaneous
Zion National Park - Scenic
Zion National Park Region - Scenic
Zuni Indians
Zygadena
Botany -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Indians of North America -- Pictorial works; Zoology -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Alaska -- Pictorial works; Bear River (Utah-Idaho) -- Pictorial works; Bryce Canyon National Park (Utah) -- Pictorial works; Canada, Western -- Pictorial works; Canadian Rockies (B.C. and Alta.) -- Pictorial works; Colorado River (Colo.-Mexico) -- Pictorial works; Glacier National Park (Mont.) -- Periodicals; Grand Canyon (Ariz.) -- Pictorial works; Isle Royale National Park (Mich.) -- Pictorial works; Mount Rainier National Park (Wash.) -- Pictorial works; United States -- Description and travel; West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Yellowstone National Park -- Pictorial works; Yosemite National Park (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Lantern slides; Photograph albums; Photographic prints; Glass plate negatives; Oastler, Frank Richard, 1871-1936
- Photograph Albums, 1912-1935; Series I; 54.2' (69 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Photograph Albums, is arranged chronologically. Many of the albums carry manuscript captions for the photographs. The albums contain miscellaneous loose items. These have been noted, and those items which when flattened were too large to fit into the album have been removed to a separate box at the end of the series, or have been placed in Oversize, as appropriate.
  - 1912
    - Glacier National Park, Montana. Album I, [1912] (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Photograph of Lower Falls, Two Medicine laid in at front, with note on back from Collins [Anderson] to Mrs. Oastler dated 1914 Apr 11
    - Glacier National Park, Montana. Album II (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Includes photographs by Kiser Photo Co. Three photographic postcards laid in loose
  - 1913
    - Glacier National Park, Montana with Yellowstone via Cody, Wyoming, I. Album I (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Album includes photographs of Blackfoot Indians
    - Glacier National Park, Montana. Album II (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Glacier National Park, Montana. Album III (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Includes photographs by Kiser Photo Co., Portland, Or.
  - 1914
    - Mount Robson Trip. Album I, [1914-15] (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Holograph poem written on Dr. Frank R. Oastler's stationery previously in envelope at front. Photographic postcards by Byron Harmon, Banff, Canada laid in loose.
      Printed maps and a letter from Joe Warner, hunter and guide to Dr. Oastler dated 1915 Mar 16, which were previously in the "Maps" envelope at the front of the album are stored in: box 69, folder 70, and Oversize, broadside folder 294
    - Mount Robson Trip. Album II, [1914] (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Photograph of pinto horse laid in loose
    - Mount Robson Trip. Album III, [1914] (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 1915
    - Wyoming. Album I, [1915] (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Wyoming. Rampart Divide. Album II, [1915] (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Wyoming. Wapiti Arch. Album III, [1915] (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - 1916
    - Grand Canyon, Arizona and New Mexico, [1916] (Box 12, Folder 12)
      Includes photographs of Indian villages (Oraibi Pueblo, Zuni Indian village). Printed material laid in loose
  - 1917
    - New Mexico. Album I, [1917] (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - New Mexico. Album II, [1917] (Box 14, Folder 14)
      Printed material and photographs laid in loose
    - New Mexico. Album III, 1916-[17] (Box 15, Folder 15)
      Letter from Fred Harvey dated 1916 Nov 13 laid in loose
  - 1918
    - Wyoming, [1918] (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Wyoming, [1918] (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Wyoming, [1918] (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - 1919
    - Wyoming. Album I, [1919] (Box 19, Folder 19)
      Photograph of a sheep laid in loose. Includes photographs by Foster Photo Co., Miles City, Mont.
    - Wyoming. Album II, [1919] (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - 1920
    - Selkirk Mountains, Canada. Album I, [1920] (Box 21, Folder 21)
      Photographs of a bear shot by guide, and bearskin laid in loose
    - Selkirk Mountains, Canada. Album II, [1920] (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Selkirk Mountains, Canada. Album III, [1920] (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - 1921
    - Canadian Rockies. Album I, [1921] (Box 24, Folder 24)
      Photograph of a half-lit tipi laid in loose
    - Canadian Rockies. Album II, [1921] (Box 25, Folder 25)
      Panoramic photographs of mountains, and photographs of Dr. Oastler with a camera and men around a campfire laid in loose
  - 1922
    - Spring: Eastern Flowers, [1922] (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Spring: Eastern Flowers, [1922] (Box 27, Folder 27)
      Photographs of flowers laid in loose
    - Summer: Motor Trip from Grand Canyon to Kayenta, Arizona. New Mexico. Bryce Canyon, Utah. Redwood Highway. Rocky Mt. National Park, [1922] (Box 28, Folder 28)
      Includes photographs by A. Wilkes
    - Summer: Arizona, Utah (Rainbow Bridge), [1922] (Box 29, Folder 29)
      Painted Desert, Blue Canyon, Grand Canyon, Arizona. Blue Forest, Havasupai Canyon, Catarack Canyon, Arizona, Rainbow Bridge Trip, Monument Valley, Adamana Petrified Forest, Arizona. Photograph laid in loose
  - 1923
    - Saskatchewan, Canada, [1923] (Box 30, Folder 30)
      Includes photographs by Asahel Curtis, F. Gowen, L.D. Lindsley
    - Mount Hood, Crater Lake, Cascade Mountains, [1923] (Box 31, Folder 31)